MORARU **ECATERINA**

PRODUCT DESIGNER

I design large-scale digital products and platforms, enjoying solutions that empower the target user. Having a technical background, I thrive collaborating with engineering teams while focusing on end-user usability. I have experience involving open source communities in the development process.

EXPERIENCE

Sep 2019 — Present

Lead Product Designer / Arezzo Sky

Designing from scratch the next-gen no-code app-creation mobile platform: from concepts, to developing the design system, to usability testing.

Nov 2015 — Aug 2019

Lead Interaction Designer / XWiki

Orchestrated the user experience across all XWiki's products. Designed tools and services that bridged the open-source community with the professional enterprise target.

Jan 2014 — Oct 2015

Applications Team Manager / XWiki

Managed a team of 5 developers in assuring a consistent user experience across 20 most valuable applications selected from over 600 open source community extensions.

Apr 2013 — Dec 2013

Front-end Team Lead / XWiki

Proposed and integrated into the XWiki Platform, the Bootstrap framework with LESS support. The result was a responsive HTML5 skin that evolved into the platform's most successful and extensible skin system, being the default skin for more than 5 major versions.

Mar 2009 — Mar 2013

Interaction Designer / XWiki

Practitioner of user experience when the field was very new. Worked on XWiki Enterprise, an open-source scalable platform for developing collaborative applications. I've designed the core features: Extension Manager, App Within Minutes, Search, Rights, Activity Stream, Administration, etc. www.risherry.ro +40 (742) 543-821 Iaşi, Romania valicac@gmail.com

user-experience / user-research interaction-design / ux-engineer prototyping / usability-testing conceptualization / design-system design-sprint / design-pattern consistency / accessibility standards-compliance / front-end roadmap-planning / open-source

COMMUNITIES

Feb 2015 — Present

Co-organizer

OpenSourceDesign.net

Growing an international community with over 3000 members that evanghelizes more open design processes in software development.

May 2008 — Nov 2019

Mentor

Google Summer of Code Introducing hundreds of students from all over the world to open source software development.

Oct 2007 — Mar 2011

Collaborator Teaching Assistant

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iaşi Pioneered teaching classes of "Human-Computer Interaction" to computer-science students.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2009

M. Sc. Software Engineering

Faculty of Computer Science. A. I. Cuza University, Iași

2003 - 2007

B. Sc. Computer Science

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iași



